Guide to the Arnold G. Dana, Class of 1883, Yale College, Scrapbook Collection Titled "Yale: Old and New"
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Arnold G. Dana, Class of 1883, Yale College, scrapbook collection titled "Yale: Old and New"
1800-1945
RU 867
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
The materials consist of 102 scrapbooks (volumes 16-18 are missing) compiled by Arnold Guyot Dana concerning Yale. The scrapbooks, collectively titled "Yale: Old and New," document various aspects of Yale, including presidents, buildings and residential colleges, publications, departments and schools, sports, finances, and student life.
Dana, Arnold Guyot, 1862-1947
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Patrons must use FILM HM 41 instead of the originals, except for volumes 16, 17, and 18, which have not been filmed.
Existence and Location of Copies
The scrapbooks are available on microfilm (19 reels, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library at cost. Order no. HM41.
Arrangement
Arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of 102 scrapbooks (volumes 16-18 are missing) compiled by Arnold Guyot Dana concerning Yale. The scrapbooks, collectively titled "Yale: Old and New," document various aspects of Yale, including presidents, buildings and residential colleges, publications, departments and schools, sports, finances, and student life.
Scrapbooks; Dana, Arnold Guyot, 1862-1947; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University -- History; Yale University -- Libraries; Yale University -- Presidents; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students
- Scrapbooks, circa 1800-1945; Accession 19ND-A-229
  - "Collegiate School" (1701-1707) Rector Pierson (Box 1, Reel 1U)
  - Rectors Andrew, Cutler, Williams, Clap (1707-1766) (Box 2, Reel 1U)
  - Early Histories (Box 2A, Reel 1U)
  - Clap (1701-1766) (Box 2A, Reel 1U)
  - Tutor Johnson on Collegiate School (Box 2A, Reel 1U)
  - Professor Dexter's Comments (Box 2A, Reel 1U)
  - James L. Kingsley History to 1835 (Box 2A, Reel 1U)
  - Presidents Dagget, Stiles, Dwight, Day (1766-1846) (Box 3, Reel 1U)
  - Presidents Woolsey, Porter, Dwight (1846-1899) (Box 4, Reel 1U)
  - Presidents Hadley, Angell, Seymour (1899-) (Box 5, Reel 1U)
  - First College House (Box 6A, Reel 2U)
  - Brick Row (Box 6B, Reel 2U)
  - Other Historic Buildings (Box 7, Reel 2U)
  - Harkness Buildings and Donors (Box 8, Reel 2U)
  - Memorial to Harkness (Box 8, Reel 2U)
  - Yale '83 (Box 8, Reel 2U)
  - Memorial Quadrangle (Box 9, Reel 2U)
  - Sculptures, Facades, Construction (Box 9, Reel 2U)
  - Architect (Box 9, Reel 2U)
  - Sculptor (Box 9, Reel 2U)
  - Residential Colleges-Branford College Courts Entires Memorials (Box 10, Reel 2U)
  - Residential Colleges-Saybrook College Courts Entries Memorials (Box 11, Reel 3U)
  - Residential Colleges-Branford and Saybrook Life and Activities (Box 11A, Reel 3U)
  - Residential Colleges-Berkeley and Calhoun (Box 12, Reel 3U)
  - Residential Colleges-Jonathan Edwards and Timothy Dwight (Box 12A, Reel 3U)
  - Residential Colleges-Davenport and Pierson (Box 13, Reel 3U)
  - Residential Colleges-Trumbull and Silliman (Box 14, Reel 3U)
  - Sterling Buildings-Life of Donor-His Buildings (Box 15, Reel 3U)
  - Yale and Her Books-Libraries on Old College Campus (*) (Box 16)
  - Sterling Library-Exterior Decorations-Floor Plan (*) (Box 17)
  - Sterling Library-Interior Views-Main Floor (*) (Box 18)
  - Sterling Library-Upper Floors-Special Collections (Box 19, Reel 4U)
  - Sterling Library-Special Collections-Other Libraries (Box 20, Reel 4U)
  - Yale Authors (Box 20G, Reel 5U)
  - Yale Official Documents (Box 20A2, Reel 5U)
  - University Press (Box 20A2, Reel 5U)
  - Yale Review (Box 20A2, Reel 5U)
  - Alumni Weekly Magazine, etc. (Box 20A2, Reel 5U)
  - Yale College (Box 20A, Reel 5U)
  - Publications, Books about Yale (Box 20A1, Reel 5U)
    General note
    See also: vol 20A-2 for Yale Alumni Reports and Official Documents
  - The University Unified (Box 20B, Reel 5U)
  - Common Freshman Year (Box 20C, Reel 5U)
  - Yale Maps (Box 20D, Reel 5U)
  - Yale's Early Professors (Box 20E, Reel 5U)
  - More Recent Professors (Box 20, Reel 6U)
  - Fine Arts and Drama (Box 21, Reel 6U)
  - Old Art Galleries (Box 21, Reel 6U)
  - Works of J. Trumbull (Box 21, Reel 6U)
  - Schools of Art and Architecture (Box 21, Reel 6U)
  - Art Work by Students and Graduates (Box 21A, Reel 6U)
  - Gallery of Fine Arts (Box 22, Reel 6U)
  - Yale Theatre and Plays A (Box 23, Reel 6U)
  - Yale Theatre and Its Plays B (Box 24, Reel 6U)
  - "The Dramat" and Earlier Plays A (Box 25, Reel 7U)
  - "The Dramat" B (Box 26, Reel 7U)
  - "The Dramat" C (Box 27, Reel 7U)
  - Law School-Early History and Buildings (Box 28, Reel 8U)
  - Sterling Law Quadrangle (Box 29, Reel 8U)
  - Professors (Box 29, Reel 8U)
  - Jurists (Box 29, Reel 8U)
  - Law Library and History (Box 29A, Reel 8U)
  - Science-Academic Department (Box 30, Reel 8U)
  - Science-Origin of Applied Science-Yale Scientific School (Box 30A, Reel 8U)
  - Sheffield Scientific School-Early History (Box 31, Reel 9U)
  - Science-Sheffield Scientific School A (Box 31A, Reel 9U)
  - Science-Sheffield Scientific School B (Box 32, Reel 9U)
  - Electrical and Mechanical Engineering, Metallurgy (Box 32, Reel 9U)
  - Van Sheff Dormitories (Box 32, Reel 9U)
  - Science-Strathcona and Sheffield Halls (Box 33, Reel 9U)
  - Sterling Chemistry (Box 33, Reel 9U)
  - Sloane Physics Laboratories (Box 33, Reel 9U)
  - Science-Zoology, Biology, Forestry Science, Zoology, Biology, Forestry (Box 34, Reel 9U)
  - Science-Astronomy (Box 35, Reel 9U)
  - Museums (Box 35, Reel 9U)
  - Kirtland Hall (Box 35, Reel 9U)
  - Mineralogy and Geology (Box 35, Reel 9U)
  - Peabody Museum (Box 35A, Reel 9U)
  - Supplementary-Anthropology, etc. (Box 35A, Reel 9U)
  - Graduate School (Box 36, Reel 10U)
  - Music School (Box 37, Reel 10U)
  - Music Clubs (Box 37A, Reel 10U)
    See also: Volume 37
  - College Chapels-Early Divinity Buildings (Box 38, Reel 10U)
  - Sterling Divinity Quadrangle-Religious Activities (Box 39, Reel 11U)
  - Yale-in-China (Box 39A, Reel 11U)
  - Old Medical School and Hospital (Box 40, Reel 11U)
  - New Haven Hospital School of Nursing University Health (Box 40A, Reel 11U)
  - Sterling School of Medicine and New Hospital Buildings (Box 41, Reel 11U)
  - Medical School in Action (Box 41A, Reel 12U)
  - Medical Floor Plans (Box 41B, Reel 12U)
  - History (Box 41B, Reel 12U)
  - Obituaries (Box 41B, Reel 12U)
  - Institute of Human Relations (Box 42, Reel 12U)
  - Psychiatry and Child Hygiene (School of Medicine) (Box 42, Reel 12U)
  - Commencement (Box 43, Reel 12U)
  - Presentation Day (Box 43A, Reel 12U)
  - Celebrations Bicentennial Founders Week 1901 (Box 43B1, Reel 13U)
    See also: folder 43B-2
  - Bicentennial-the Pageant 1916: The Removal to New Haven Other Celebrations (Box 43B2, Reel 13U)
  - Life at Yale (Box 44, Reel 13U)
  - Life at Yale vol II (Box 44A, Reel 13U)
  - "Town and Gown" Rushes, etc. (Box 45, Reel 13U)
  - Cartoons and Campus Characters (Box 46, Reel 13U)
  - Senior Societies Honor Societies (Box 47, Reel 14U)
  - Junior Societies and Fraternities Alive and Dead (Box 48, Reel 14U)
  - Clubs A Sheffield Law Medical (Box 49, Reel 14U)
  - Clubs B Debating Mory's Whiffenpoofs Graduates Faculty Yale N. Y. (Box 50, Reel 14U)
  - Defunct Societies and Old Eating Clubs Sophomores and Freshmen (Box 51, Reel 14U)
  - Publications (Box 52, Reel 15U)
  - Periodicals-Students' and Graduates' (Box 52, Reel 15U)
  - Yale Gym Yale Bowl Yale Field, etc. (Box 52A, Reel 15U)
  - Boating A (Box 53, Reel 15U)
  - Boating B (Box 54, Reel 16U)
  - Football A (Box 55, Reel 16U)
  - Football B (Box 56, Reel 16U)
  - Baseball A (Box 57, Reel 16U)
  - Baseball B (Box 58, Reel 16U)
  - Swimming (Box 59A, Reel 17U)
  - Other Sports A (Box 59, Reel 17U)
  - Other Sports B (Box 60, Reel 17U)
  - The Executive Officers (Box 60A, Reel 17U)
  - Financial History-Financial Drives 1716-1920 (Box 61, Reel 17U)
  - Financial History (Box 62, Reel 18U)
  - Twenty Million Endowment Drive (Box 63, Reel 18U)
  - Total Endowments 1917-1941 (Box 64, Reel 18U)
  - Alumni Fund (Box 65, Reel 18U)
  - The Corporation and Fellows (Box 66, Reel 18U)
  - Internal Reconstruction (Box 67, Reel 18U)
  - Chronology (Box 68, Reel 18U)
  - Preparatory Schools (Box 69, Reel 18U)
  - War Years through World War I (Box 70, Reel 19U)
  - War Years-World War II (Box 71, Reel 19U)
  - Famous Men and Classes (Box 72, Reel 19U)
  - Yale Then and Now (Box 73, Reel 19U)
  - Bibliography (Box 74, Reel 19U)
  - Yale rectors, presidents, and buildings (Box 75)